## Anthony Rivers

## **Anthony Rivers**

Fanwood, NJ

(908)-294-2646

**Software Developer** 

https://hirerivers.netlify.app/ hireriversanthony@gmail.com

https://github.com/rememberanthonyrivers

Skills

Languages: Python, Javascript, HTML5, CSS 3, SQL, JSON, JSX, Bash, Git

Software: React, Flask, Django, NodeJS, Microsoft Office Suite

Other: Verbal and written skills, Interdepartmental communication, presentation,

financial products and derivatives.

## Summary

Computer scientist of 5 years with a strong foundation in data structures, mathematics, and the ability to develop practical solutions that prioritize both performance and security. My education has provided me with a wealth of experience in the areas of web development, database design, and software engineering.

## **Experience**

#### Software Developer — Coding Temple, Chicago, IL

**APRIL 2023 - JULY 2023** 

- Architected and constructed visually appealing, user-friendly responsive web pages and interfaces using HTML5, CSS 3, and Javascript.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to integrate front-end and back-end code.
- Tested and debugged web pages and interfaces to ensure proper functionality across different browsers and devices.
- Optimized website performance, Stayed up-to-date with new technologies to improve workflow and work quality.
- Worked together with designers to ensure web application aligns with clients vision and brand identity.
- Strong RESTful API knowledge: Proficient in building scalable and resourceful APIs following industry best practices.

### Data Analyst — Coding Temple, Chicago, IL

JAN 2023 - APR 2023

- Analyzed and visualized data using Python Libraries like Matplotlib, and Plotly to create insightful charts and graphs.
- Collected and processed data from various sources using Python Libraries such as Pandas and Numpy.

- Skilled in crafting high quality reports and presentation that clearly communicate the results of data analysis to a wide range of stakeholders, including senior management
- Cleaned and transformed data using Python Libraries such as Pandas to ensure accuracy and consistency

#### Administrative Assistant — H&R Block, Chatham, NJ

#### FEB 2023 - MAY 2023

- Assisted with tax preparation by gathering and organizing client information, inputting data into tax software, printing and mailing tax returns
- Maintained Accurate and up-to-date client records.
- Handled confidential client information with discretion and ensured that it is securely stored.
- Greeted clients, collected information, and ensured all necessary forms and documentation were completed.

#### Executive Assistant - Mobit2 Care Services, Union, NJ

#### JUNE 2023 - PRESENT

- Maintained and updated accurate records containing client information
- Resolved customer complaints: Listened to customer concerns and provided solutions
- Provided support and information between teams in regards to client records

## **Relevant Projects**

**Sensor Data Logger (2023 Personal)**: Simulates a fire alarm sensor and logs temperature readings into a CSV file. It demonstrates the concept of data collection and storage using Python.

**India Real Estate Case Study (2022 Personal)**: Engineered Python data analysis using Pandas, NumPy, and Matplotlib to drive actionable insights for future market development.

**Car Dealership Database with ERD (2021 Academic)**: Led a small team which designed and implemented backend databases utilizing SQL.

# Education / Achievements

## **Coding Temple / Python Software Development Certification**

Software Development Bootcamp JANUARY 2023-JULY 2023, Chicago, IL

#### Union College / A.A.S. Computer Science

SEPTEMBER 2018-MAY 2020, Cranford, NJ